♪
[wind blowing]
-[creaking]
-[Coco gasps softly]
Is that the wind?
-[QIFREY] Ah, you're awake.
-Huh?
[Qifrey grunts softly]
I took the liberty of hailing us
a Pegasus Carriage.
[COCO] Huh?
You must be chilly,
flying so high
in your bedclothes.
Our ride's almost over.
-Oh, look there.
-[Coco gasps]
Our destination.
[Coco gasps]
[gasps]
♪
[QIFREY] That is my atelier.
And your new place of study.
[♪ opening theme song playing]
THE SCHOOL OF THE GRASSLAND
[QIFREY] Don't worry
about your house.
I planted Guard Briar seeds
all around it.
They'll grow quickly,
and as they do,
they'll form
a protective barrier.
The spell that petrified
your house,
is presently unknown to us.
Best to keep
any careless visitors
from getting too close.
Well, then...
Uh?
Coco?
What's the matter?
[crying]
I promised my mother
that I would never leave her
all alone,
and now, I...
Oh, dear.
Please don't blame yourself.
You didn't know.
[door closes]
[footsteps]
♪
[QIFREY] Here,
to wash your face.
Let your tears fall behind you,
and look forward.
As of today,
this shall be your home.
[Coco gasps]
[COCO] Uh...
-[COCO] Um, what is this?
-[QIFREY] Hm?
Why, it's water.
Oh, right.
How could I forget?
You'll need a change of clothes.
[COCO] Water isn't usually
so round and floaty.
-I'll be back in a flash.
-[gasps]
Wait, could you explain
how I'm supposed
to use this first?
Mr. Qifrey?
Touching magic
I know nothing about
is a little scary now.
[GIRL] Aw, don't be scared!
Far as spells go,
that one's pretty simple.
[chuckles]
I can tell you all about it
if you want me to!
[Coco gasps softly]
What you've got there
is a Vapor Bubble.
It's a kind of magic that takes
moisture out of the air
and turns it into water.
Hold out your hands for me.
Here! Go on!
You tilt the lower tray
like this,
and the water comes flowing out!
Wow, amazing.
Thanks so much.
-Thank you!
-[COCO] Huh?
I always love it so when
people tell me "thank you."
So thank you for your thanks!
[COCO] Oh, I see.
Well, thank you, again.
And thank you!
That one's
for thanking me again!
Thank you too!
Thank you for thanking me
-for thanking you.
-[GIRL 2] Stop responding,
-just ignore her.
-[both gasp]
She'll tire herself out
and give up.
Richeh, you're so mean!
I was actually being
very helpful,
I'll have you know.
[Coco gasps]
[COCO] The pen and ink.
Would the two of you
happen to be witches?
We're apprentices.
Students studying
with Master Qifrey.
Wait, if you're asking,
then are you not?
So what are you?
Are you the same age
as Richeh and I?
Are you? Looks like it.
And what atelier
did you come here from?
[Coco exhales nervously]
Well, uh, I think
it's still a little early
to call myself a student.
The truth is, before yesterday,
I had never drawn
a spell in my life.
But I do live here
starting today.
[BOTH] Oh...
What is it?
So it's you.
You're the one
that rumor's about?
What do you mean?
What rumor?
[exclaims softly]
♪
[GIRL] People have been
talking about an Outsider
who made use of forbidden magic,
and was then allowed
to become an apprentice
with her memories intact.
-[QIFREY] Coco?
-[Coco gasps]
Are you all right?
I think so.
Looks as though you've all been
getting acquainted
with each other.
Richeh, Tetia,
once you're finished helping
with the morning chores,
will you go study in your rooms?
-All right!
-Hm.
[QIFREY] Here. It's what
all my students wear.
[Coco exclaims softly]
Please don't worry.
I will explain everything.
[birds chirping]
[QIFREY]
Looks like a perfect fit.
[Coco exhales softly]
And now, I shall share with you
the history of magic.
[Coco gasps softly] Hm.
[QIFREY] Long ago...
magic was a part
of ordinary life.
[scribbling]
All that one needed to use it
was a special ink
and a set of patterns.
♪
[QIFREY] It was a simple,
familiar tool,
available to anyone
and everyone.
Yet at the same time,
it was a constant source
of conflict.
[faint clamoring]
[QIFREY] When mankind holds
the power to do anything,
"anything" is what they do.
Many horrific spells
were created.
The few good souls
who remained in the world
renounced war and strife,
and banded together
as witches.
They stole away
humanity's memory of magic,
letting it only be known
to their disciples,
who were sworn to protect it.
That was the Day of the Pact.
Since then,
people have believed
that magic is a power
only a chosen few can wield.
If the truth came to light,
the world would fall
into chaos once again.
You see, that's why
we've taken such care
to preserve the secret.
And why your story
has traveled so quickly.
I'm sorry.
No.
I've brought
all this upon myself.
But...
What is "forbidden magic"?
Magic drawn
during the age of war,
and banished upon
the Day of the Pact.
Magic for hurting people.
[Coco gasps]
[COCO] Teach me, I beg you!
Let me learn about
this Forbidden Magic!
I need to understand it!
I can't go on not knowing.
It's too frightening to bear!
Normally, I tell my students
not to rush themselves,
but I fear
it's too late for that.
Come with me.
There are any number
of forbidden spells
I could list.
But to keep it simple,
it's like so...
Any spell cast directly
upon the human body
is utterly prohibited.
This includes transformation,
age alteration,
teleportation without the use
of doors or conveyances.
Manipulating thoughts
or emotions,
doing harm to a person,
or healing them.
There is but one exception.
Erasing people's memories?
[QIFREY] Precisely...
Therefore, most spells
are cast on tools.
Like carriages, or lamps.
[gasps] Wow.
Or even windows,
such as this one.
It's a lake!
But we were surrounded by hills
just a moment ago.
[QIFREY] This is a Windowway.
It links two round windows
bearing the same pattern.
Do you see that building
in the distance?
The Tower of Tomes.
Every time a book on magic
is written,
a copy instantly appears there,
to ensure the knowledge within
is never lost.
[Coco gasps]
They'll have the picture book.
Please take me there!
I'll search nonstop
till I find it!
Slow down.
[water gushing]
[rumbling]
-[Qifrey grunts]
-[Coco exclaims]
[Coco groans]
♪
[chuckles]
That's the Librarians' Trial.
The Tower of Tomes is guarded
by four librarians,
and only witches
who overcome their trials
are allowed to enter.
So if you wish to visit,
you're going to have to study.
Coco...
Hearing of your
eagerness to learn
truly filled me with happiness.
And the fear you feel
is natural.
But...
the spells which have
not been forbidden...
are the ones that bring
happiness to people's lives.
Don't you think
you'd rather learn about
a gentler kind of magic?
-[Coco gasps]
-[QIFREY] What do you say?
[COCO] Huh?
Are you interested?
Yes.
Of course, Master Qifrey.
[bird cawing]
This will be your room.
Apparently Agott's not around.
[COCO] Who's Agott?
[QIFREY]
She's your new roommate.
[Coco exclaims softly]
[QIFREY] There's one workspace,
which you'll share,
and two bedrooms.
[Coco gasps]
[QIFREY] They're down the stairs
in the back.
Don't worry, the doors do lock.
Get some rest if you like.
I had better be on my way.
Call me if you need anything.
[footsteps]
Hello, this is Qifrey.
Coco's settling in nicely.
Thank you for approving
her apprenticeship.
Yes.
No.
Nothing on the book yet.
She may need a bit of time
to get adjusted.
[Coco exclaims]
[COCO] So this is what
a witch's room looks like.
[AGOTT]
That's my side of the desk.
[Coco gasps]
Out of the way. I'm landing.
Oh, I'm sorry.
[exclaims softly]
Nice to meet you!
-Agott, right? I'm Coco...
-I know.
The famous Outsider, right?
I understand you'll be
joining us as an apprentice.
Oh, right.
Sorry to hear
about your mother.
Thanks. That's very kind.
[AGOTT] Because of you...
she'll never be flesh
and blood again, will she?
[Coco inhales sharply]
The reason I'm here
is to save her, if I can.
By becoming a witch...
This is what my life has been.
Drawing casting seals
till my fingers turned black.
Working and working
to pass the tests,
so that one day
I could become an apprentice.
You don't know
the first thing about it.
There's no way
an Outsider like you
will ever be a witch.
♪
No, I don't know.
But I have drawn spells!
I have to at least try!
All right, then prove yourself.
Your test starts tomorrow--
[TETIA] Agott! Coco!
Food time!
-Let's go!
-[stomach growls]
[COCO] Excuse me!
I could eat a Pegasus.
I could, too!
And this will be
Coco's welcome party!
-Such fun!
-Such food.
♪
Normal meal. Ugh.
Um, Master,
where's the welcome party?
No time to prepare.
We'll just have it
some other day.
Where's Agott?
"I'm eating in my room."
It's her choice,
but I do wish she'd join us
every once in a while.
Now, we don't want it
to get cold, do we?
It's your day, Coco.
Would you bless
the meal for us?
[COCO] Oh! Um...
We're grateful for this food.
[ALL] We're grateful
for this food.
[COCO] Mm...
It's so good.
It is, isn't it?
And we bake it ourselves.
Master's an excellent chef.
He is!
It's the locally grown wheat
that makes the difference.
[Coco exclaims softly]
[exclaims]
This area's vegetables
are of superior quality as well.
-[COCO] Thanks! Delicious!
-Thank you, Master Qifrey!
♪
[COCO] Mom... [sniffles]
[birds chirping]
[COCO] So I need
to take tests of some kind
in order to become
an apprentice.
But it sure would be nice
to get some specifics
on what exactly it is
I have to do.
[QIFREY]
Do about what, exactly?
[Coco gasps]
There's a great deal about magic
you won't find in any book.
Trust me, it's best to learn
by doing. So here.
What are they?
Your components,
tools for drawing magic.
Oh, wow!
Amazing!
[gasps]
A pen, just like the wand.
It still scares me to hold this.
But no...
Mom, I'm going to save you
no matter what!
Please, Master Qifrey,
I'm ready to learn!
Good, let's begin.
[QIFREY]
Are you all right, Coco?
Shall we take a break?
[COCO] No. I'm fine.
Very well.
Why don't you sum up
all that you've learned so far?
Sounds good.
Let's see, to start with,
a spell is composed
of three elements.
The sigil lies in the center.
It's surrounded by
markings called signs.
And then, the outer circle
that completes it,
that's called the ring.
The types of sigil are Fire,
Water,
Light,
and Wind.
They determine
what kind of magic it is.
The signs determine what form
the magic ultimately takes,
as well as its size
and direction.
Lastly, when the outer ring
is completed,
that locks the seal in place
and activates the spell.
Memorizing all this is
really taking it out of me.
But you explained it,
that's what counts!
Right. I'm going to try
drawing one now!
Good for you! That's the spirit!
[Coco sighs]
[Coco exclaims softly]
[QIFREY] Uh?
-[Coco grunts]
-[Qifrey gasps]
-[QIFREY] Don't throw it away.
-[gasps]
No! Please don't look!
It's not even worthy
of your attention!
It's sloppy,
and the lines are all wobbly,
and it's a great big mess.
Of course it is.
You're only just learning.
To that end, here's something
you may want to look at.
See this spot?
Your ring doesn't fully connect.
Unless the circle is complete,
the spell won't activate.
[COCO] Oh.
[QIFREY]
It's natural to be unsteady
when you're getting used
to something new.
You're like a foal
that's just learning to stand.
Don't you worry.
You'll be running wild
in no time at all.
Now, connect the lines,
and activate the spell.
-[Coco screams]
-[Qifrey gasps]
I am so sorry!
It was an accident!
I didn't mean to!
[Coco screams]
[COCO] I am
so, so, so, so sorry.
Let me dry it off. [pants]
-Is it working?
-[QIFREY] Settle down, Coco!
Apologies, Agott.
-Are you all right?
-[COCO] Better?
Perfectly fine.
I'm really not bothered
in the least.
But may I ask for a look
at the casting seal she drew?
[QIFREY] Oh, yes.
[AGOTT] Ah, here's the problem.
[Coco exclaims softly]
[AGOTT] Look...
This sign is longer
than the others.
It amplified the pressure
in this direction,
causing the water
to come gushing out.
[QIFREY] Well done!
Astutely observed, as always.
[Qifrey sighs]
Yes, she should be in
very good hands with you.
[COCO] Huh?
For the next few days,
I'm going to be away
visiting the Great Hall.
While I'm gone,
do look after her,
won't you, Agott?
I will. Of course.
[door opens]
Wait! Hold on!
One may learn much indeed
from their peers.
You'll see. Watch her closely
and take it all in.
[Coco gasps]
But, Master, I...
[door closes]
Um, I am sorry
about before. I never--
I said I wasn't bothered,
didn't I?
So you can stop apologizing.
-More importantly...
-[gasps]
I told you to prove yourself,
and I intend to make you.
As of now,
the cushy little lessons
are over.
And your test has begun.
[COCO] What...
♪
[♪ closing theme song playing]
EPISODE 3:
THE DADAH RANGE TEST